Narrator: Part 1
R: …her story is one of determination and hard graft,
which took her from leaving school at 15 with nothing to the icon of elegant living she is today.
But, Jo, what went wrong with your schooling?
J: Um, I was dyslexic – I am dyslexic, horribly – and it, but it wasn’t…
it wasn’t discovered until I’d left school.
So, I can remember at the age of 11 cheating in an exam because
I was so fed up being the bottom in the class, and so I looked at a multiple choice,
and I could copy the multiple choice. And I was caught, rightly so,
and made to stand on my chair, and the teacher turned round and said to me,
‘You are lazy and stupid, and you’ll never make anything of your life.’
I don’t blame her, you know, what she was – she was dealing with a situation at the time
– but I knew I was neither. I was smart, I was clever, I was hard-working,
I just learned in a very different fashion.
R: Because that can go either way, can’t it?
You can either, sort of, take that on board and feel crushed by it, or you can think,
‘Actually, I’m not accepting that.’
J: I think I’ve lived my life not being defined by other people’s opinions of me.
Everyone’s always got an opinion of you, haven’t they?
They…and you can either allow yourself to be defined by that, or you move on.
And I knew – I knew I was always two steps ahead, so, I could make face creams,
I could do all sorts of different things, so, I could do things that other children couldn’t do.
R: Great knowledge to have for an entrepreneur, isn’t it?
And you did start out very early; I mean,
you were on market stalls selling your dad’s paintings and stuff,
and learning the rudiments of, um, how to encourage people to buy.
J: Yeah, I loved that, absolutely.
So, I had three jobs when I was little – one was the market stall.
So, I would go from the age of seven.
I’d go with my dad to Crayford, Dartford, Blackheath, Tunbridge Wells,
and he was a painter, and we came from a very poor background,
so we had lived in a two-up, two-down,
and as I would walk through the door on a Saturday morning to go to the market my mum would say,
‘There’s no food in the fridge, Jo. If you don’t sell a painting, there is nothing to eat.’
So, I knew my job…
R: No pressure!
J: Well…But, you know something?
When you grow up like that, it feels like the most natural thing for you.
You don’t feel like, you know, ‘poor’. I didn’t ever feel ‘poor me’, by the way, ever.
So, I knew I would always have to sell the first painting very quickly, and I did,
and I’d pocket the money, knowing that we had enough to pay the rent,
or, you know, certainly put a couple of meals in the fridge.